Zilola Nazarova

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

ziloladev@gmail.com | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Wellfound | Medium

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a background in architecture and a love for UX/UI. Embrace and excel in the realm of mathematics and arts. Proficient in multiple languages, frameworks and technologies like Ruby on Rails, React and JavaScript. Experienced in pair programming and remote work, quick to adapt. Fast learner and multitasker.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

Graphical Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, CorelDraw, Figma

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

May 2023 - Present

SmartPocket - keep track of your expenses - create, update, delete transactions and group them into categories

• Built with: Ruby on Rails. View the repository on GitHub

Blog App — read posts of app users, sign in to write your own posts or interact with other posts (like and comment)

• Built with: Ruby on Rails. View the repository on GitHub

Mountains Forecast — see current weather conditions and hourly forecasts for peaks; add new locations

Built with: React, Redux and Ruby on Rails. View the repository on GitHub

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

September 2023 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program

TOSHUYJOYLITI

MICROVERSE

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Apr 2019 - May 2023

Architect, Aseismic Construction Department

- Rendered models of innovative constructions which were presented at the UzBuild 2020 exhibition
- Performed calculations and documentation of innovative constructions that were patented internationally (IAP 20180364)
- Earned a promotion over 1 year for updating 8 building codes (approved by the Ministry of Construction)

EDUCATION

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

Remote

May 2023 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers

TASHKENT INSTITUTE OF ARCHITECTURE AND CIVIL ENGINEERING Bachelors, Architecture

Tashkent, Uzbekistan Sep 2013 – Feb 2018

Participated in an exchange program at the Hanbat National University (South Korea)